<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mediasmart</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/</id><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>mediasmart launches new programmatic console for mobile media buying and campaign management</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-new-programmatic-console" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-09-14:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-new-programmatic-console</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intuitive and complete self-service interface, with industry-first integrated customer support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mediasmart Mobile - a company that licenses its leading mobile DSP (Demand Side Platform), has unveiled its new console, empowering customers to access award winning programmatic technology through an easy to use interface that dramatically enhances the process of creating and managing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an enhancement to its traditional offering - one of the first to market in the mobile programmatic space - the new web application and API has been built from scratch and beta tested by mediasmart customers for the past eight months. It offers many new features, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An enhanced user experience that is extremely fast to load and operate, allowing users to quickly navigate through the multiple options within an advertising campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wizard that guides customers through the basic steps required to set up their campaigns and a context-sensitive guide to explain the concepts within each area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An industry first customer care section integrated into the app itself, allowing users to easily report any issues and interact directly with the mediasmart team for effective resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“With fast execution and management now crucial to a successful mobile campaign, mediasmart’s console has quickly become one of our most used technologies. As one of the most advanced tools in our arsenal, it allows us to rapidly manage and optimize our campaigns, through the most user-friendly interface out there.”&lt;/em&gt; – Says Nicolas Saraiva, Head of Media Buying &amp;amp; Operations @ Mozoo Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interface is also fully customizable, allowing customers to adapt the look and feel to their brand, and is accessible through mobile devices (iOs 7+ and Android 5+), allowing customers to easily work outside of the office. It offers online and email notifications as well, to instantly inform customers of activity within campaigns requiring immediate action and to provide recommendations so that they can stay in constant control of their campaigns. Together with a range of sophisticated reporting and analysis tools, this helps mediasmart customers act faster on any issues affecting their campaigns and maximize results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our ambition is to provide the best mobile first DSP in the marketplace. The new console is not only the best user interface for the platform, but also the best foundation to easily incorporate new features and guarantee speed of operation”&lt;/em&gt;, says Javier Jiménez, Head of Product at mediasmart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Having the best user experience is absolutely critical to scale and cope with the exponential market growth we are seeing. Thanks to the work we´ve done with our beta customers in the past eight months, we are very confident that the upgrade will be well received”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More about &lt;a href="http://mediasmart.io/about-us"&gt;mediasmart Mobile&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mediasmart_mb"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>A Programmatic Vision for Private Exchanges</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/a-programmatic-vision-for-private-exchanges" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-09-02:mediasmart-pelican/blog/a-programmatic-vision-for-private-exchanges</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The recent Global Mobile Programmatic Trends Report for Q1 2016, suggests that mobile is now aligning with the most established advertising channels. With mobile programmatic now a fully fledged digital channel and a highly successful force in its own right, some say that part of the revenue growth from high-impact inventory is the result of the rise in the number of private exchanges. Noelia Amoedo, CEO, Mediasmart agrees with this statement. Writing exclusively for ExchangeWire, Amoedo explains why private exchanges might be driving this growth and how the use of private exchanges needs to become more automated to ensure efficient inventory discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private exchanges have made many publishers feel more comfortable with the whole programmatic world and in many cases have been the reason why some premium publishers have decided to ‘go programmatic’. They definitely allow for a less ‘shocking’ transition than going straight to open auctions, at least from a perception perspective. As the ecosystem matures and the open marketplace starts to fully reflect the prices from true market demand, we’re likely to see an increasing amount of inventory going through open marketplaces but, today, private marketplaces are not to be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now however, there are many things that still remain to be done if we want private exchanges to be more ‘automated’, so that we don’t recreate the inefficient legacy ways of planning all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mobile, the purchasing tools currently available make the process of discovering inventory in private ad exchanges rather inefficient and, as a result, publishers will still need to sell to advertisers directly if they want their very good and more expensive inventory to be noticed. The majority of mobile-first SSPs don’t even offer an online discovery tool. In fact, most information about available inventory on private deals is typically presented in spreadsheet form and shared on demand or on an ad hoc basis with potential buyers. Even in those few cases where there is an online inventory tool, they tend to differ for each SSP, so potential purchasers must log in into different tools to gain a view of available inventory.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need discovery APIs for demand side platforms to be able to build comprehensive tools that give an immediate view to advertisers of what’s available. In the case of mediasmart, of the 27 exchanges we are currently connected to, only three offer part of what is needed, with only a further one or two planning to make it available in the medium term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so few providers making these available and no industry standard being proposed, even if SSPs start to make discovery APIs available, they will each develop their own API, so development is going to be complicated to manage and maintain for any DSP that connects to a lot of SSPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until standard APIs are ready and demand side platforms integrate them within comprehensive tools, the process of buying on private exchanges will remain a manual one, with advertisers contacting publishers or their SSPs directly, exchanging emails and phone calls or looking at excels – a situation that is very far from what is expected in a programmatic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read More in &lt;a href="https://www.exchangewire.com2016/09/01/programmatic-vision-private-exchanges/"&gt;ExchangeWire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Monetisation and the data game</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/monetisation-and-the-data-game" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-07-08:mediasmart-pelican/blog/monetisation-and-the-data-game</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marketers and mobile game developers are increasingly using data to better monetise their apps, via in-app purchases and advertising. If you are a game developer there’s strong scope for adding as much user data to your inventory as possible, to maximise your yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst obtaining demographic info from a user remains difficult, you can still gather some useful behavioral patterns. Gathering granular information is relatively easy. This can be about the context where the ads are going to be seen; which games are being played, which sections within games and what´s the user ID alongside their location, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This offers enhanced monetisation opportunities because it allows programmatic advertisers to automatically optimise their output in each section of the game. Advertisers can then pay more for the users and contexts that work best for them, especially if they use the right tools to maximise campaign engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the data element, the second lever available to maximise yield is the ever important factor of ad formats – and usually, the more sophisticated formats are, the higher price advertisers are willing to pay for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sophistication must be balanced by proper standards however, or effective reach is lost. Rewarded video and native ads are the clear recommendation today, as they have both become standards in the programmatic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewarded video is the most effective way to monetise in games, but it’s worth noting that native ads are also effective monetisers. In the gaming industry the opportunity has not been fully realised however, with many still focusing on the more widely adopted video formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to data, a challenge exists between publisher and advertiser objectives. Publishers are already trying to get up to speed with these formats and most of them are also clear on the fact that use of data is critical to maximize yield, but they remain very protective around their data, and this is often in conflict with the interests of the advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishers want advertisers to take advantage of data, but they also want the data to stay within their own perimeters, through contracts and private deal creation. For example, they will assure an advertiser that a given user is a woman, but they will not allow the advertiser to keep that information so that they can target that woman with another publisher. In some cases they will simply not provide the user ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisers would argue that when they pay to serve an impression to a user they’re entitled to the data and information held by the publisher. So publishers that protect their data this way will simply be less attractive to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, handling data through mechanisms such as deal IDs also presents a challenge. They require a direct interaction between the advertiser and the publisher, which slows down processes and offers less revenue for the game developer. Ultimately, this issue is causing a great deal of manual work in a world where programmatic offers automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reluctance by some publishers is based on their thinking that if they give the data away then advertisers wouldn’t need to buy from them anymore. In practice however, advertisers may actually buy more from a publisher that consistently shares data in an effort to precisely increase their access to valuable data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Elusive Art of Gaming Monetisation</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-elusive-art-of-gaming-monetisation" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-06-08:mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-elusive-art-of-gaming-monetisation</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gaming monetisation is considered by some as a dirty practice; but, with the gaming category accounting for the highest share (23%) of the billions of downloaded apps, the fact can’t be ignored that gaming is a powerful business, with extremely rich sets of data. Noelia Amoedo, CEO, Mediasmart and Grant Gudgel, COO, SMRTR.MEDIA (both pictured), share their expertise with ExchangeWire on how game developers can leverage data to optimise monetisation, whilst highlighting the challenges faced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant Gudgel, COO, SMRTR.MEDIA: Best practice gaming monetisation
Mobile game developers are now seizing the opportunity to use data to better monetise their apps, and they’re doing this via two types of monetisation: in-app purchases and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within these, it’s important to consider different approaches for both new and engaged users, however. When a new user connects, the first objective is to get the user ‘hooked’ to the game. This allows you to analyse the game play data to optimise the user experience and keep people coming back to play further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once users are engaged, the goal is slightly different. For a user who is already ‘hooked’, the opportunity then exists to monetise. The process here is to analyse behavioural data, find and remedy the moment of frustration, and then segment the audience data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through analysis of the behavioural data behind a gamers activity – for example, which game items is he or she is using most, you can then propose paid upgrades to those specific item categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game developers would then look for the user’s ‘moment of frustration’, where the gamer becomes frustrated about his or her progress and intends to quit the game. Slightly before this ‘choke point’, where many users lose and leave the app, you can then propose an in-app purchase to help the gamer progress further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Segmenting audience data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then come to segmenting the audience data according to those who pay and those who don’t. For users who pay, we look to monetise wherever possible. For those who don’t, we first try to convert them to paying with promotions such as, “Get 20 new lives for the price of 10!!!” type incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also segment the audience data into users who continue to pay, and those who don’t. Either way, all are incentivised to invite their friends to play the game and the game can then be further monetised with ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Non-paying users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final goal is to monetise non-paying users. For the 90% of players who will never make an in-app purchase, we separate them out and use non-intrusive ads to monetise where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewarded video tends to work best for this – so, we continue to propose in-app purchases, but include the option to make the purchase by watching a short video ad.
By getting people to use in-app purchases through rewarded ads, we often see increased conversion rates of people who became more engaged with the game and do, finally, convert to becoming paying users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s important to analyse user behaviour to optimise ad frequency and engagement, we also need to avoid saturating the audience with ads that cause users to stop using the game or app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways to do this, and it ultimately comes down to attrition analysis – i.e., looking at who starts leaving the app because of ads. That said, if the ads are done right, you should be able to generate reasonable ad revenue from non-paying users without excessive attrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Noelia Amoedo, CEO, Mediasmart: The mobile media buying perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once game developers have set up the best practice user workflow described by Gudgel, there’s strong scope for adding as much user data to your inventory as possible, to maximise your yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gathering purely demographic info, such as age range and gender, etc. is clearly important to attract brand advertisers. But, it may not be easy to get from the user and, depending on the game, not easy to deduct. You can still gather some useful behavioural patterns, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also provide as much granular information as possible about the context where the ads are going to be seen: which games, which sections within games, the user ID, and user location, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way, monetisation can be enhanced further because it allows programmatic advertisers to automatically optimise their output in each section of the game. Advertisers can then pay more for the users and contexts that work best for them, especially if they use the right tools to maximise campaign engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Formats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the data element, the second lever available to maximise yield is the ever-important factor of ad formats – and, usually, the more sophisticated, the higher price advertisers are willing to pay for them. This sophistication must also be balanced by proper standards, however, or effective reach is lost. Rewarded video and native ads are the clear recommendation today, as they have both become standards in the programmatic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewarded video is the most effective way to monetise in games; but it’s worth noting that native ads are also effective monetisers. In the gaming industry, the opportunity has not been fully realised, however, with many still focusing on the more widely adopted video formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishers are already trying to get up to speed with these formats, and at Mediasmart we’re supporting the ecosystem with effective audience targeting and engagement optimisation. They are clear on the fact that use of data is critical to maximise yield; but they remain very protective around their data, and this is often in conflict with the interests of the advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishers want advertisers to take advantage of data, but they also want the data to stay within their own perimeters, through contracts and private deal creation. For example, they will ensure an advertiser that a given user is a woman, but they will not allow the advertiser to keep that information so that they can target that woman with another publisher. In some cases, they will simply not provide the user ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisers would argue that when they pay to serve an impression to a user they’re entitled to the data and information held by the publisher. So, publishers that protect their data this way will simply be less attractive to them. On the other hand, handling data through mechanisms such as deal IDs presents a challenge as well. They require a direct interaction between the advertiser and the publisher, which slows down processes and offers less revenue for the game developer. Ultimately, this issue is causing a great deal of manual work in a world where programmatic offers automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, if you want to achieve massive audience demand and monetise ads effectively, you need to use programmatic and all the benefits that come with it – and one of those benefits is the use of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some may think you’d be reluctant to give it away because then advertisers wouldn’t need to buy from you anymore. The reality, however, is that advertisers may actually buy more from you precisely because they can get more data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mediasmart and Ligatus partner</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-ligatus-partner" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-05-19:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-ligatus-partner</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mediasmart Mobile – a mobile technology company whose DSP (Demand Side Platform) optimizes the media buying process to maximize engagement – has partnered with Ligatus, Europe’s leading Native and Performance Network, to allow its native advertising inventory to be available to buy programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivering more than 31 billion ad impressions per month on over 1,200 premium sites, Ligatus native formats inventory is now available through mediasmart, mediasmart´s proprietary technology platform. Mediasmart´s customers can access it on a self-serve basis, either through mediasmart web interface or via mediasmart APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement will help boost customer demand, and maximize user engagement and monetization capabilities for Ligatus inventory. It should also enable advertisers to maximize engagement and deliver the best possible results, using the combination of mediasmart´s predictive targeting algorithms and Ligatus’ hand-picked premium publishers (which are fraud-free and proven to deliver high conversion rates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mediasmart’s mediasmart platform ran campaigns in 58 countries last year. This new global partnership will strengthen supply in Europe and is part of the company´s continuous efforts to add value through non-intrusive formats, as CEO, Noelia Amoedo explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Native formats provide a great deal of information about the product or service being advertised, and offer a more qualified interaction with a clear call to action. This far more effective format than display ads, maximizes conversion rates and engagement whilst improving the user experience in a non-intrusive way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmatic demand for native ad formats has grown significantly recently. It is also understood that native formats are an effective way to address ad blocker challenges, because they are relevant, customized, non-invasive and part of the actual content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Advertisers want to buy programmatically in native formats, so this is a promising growth market for Ligatus”, said Klaus Ludemann, CEO of Ligatus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This agreement will allow us to reach new advertisers through mediasmart´s DSP and promote the buying process of this type of format in Europe, where demand is extremely high and we are receiving many requests. At the same time our publishers benefit from this increased demand by getting a better monetarisation of their inventory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ABOUT LIGATUS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ligatus is the #1 Native and Performance Network in Europe and a 100 percent subsidiary of the publisher Gruner + Jahr in Hamburg. Ligatus is focussing on Direct Response Campaigns and Content Promotion. Besides its headquarter in Germany the leading Premium Performance Marketing Vendor in Europe is active in Austria, Switzerland, France, Belgium, the Netherlands, Spain, Italy and Turkey. Across Europe, Ligatus has more than 150 employees at these locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The innovative technology offers advertisers and agencies an intelligent placement of their advertising messages. The invoicing mode, which is exclusively success-dependent, allows optimum cost control. Premium publishers achieve an optimal monetization of their content thanks to the advertising formats of Ligatus. In addition, the specialized recommendation technologies enable them to increase their traffic significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Europe, Ligatus delivers more than 31 billion ad impressions per month on over 1,200 Premium partner sites in nine countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information: &lt;a href="www.ligatus.com"&gt;www.ligatus.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mediasmart and Gameloft partner</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-gameloft-partner" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-04-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-04-06:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-gameloft-partner</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gameloft Advertising Solutions has partnered with mediasmart Mobile – a company that licenses its leading mobile DSP (Demand Side Platform), helping its clients optimize their mobile media buying process – to make Gameloft inventory programmatically available through mediasmart’s mediasmart platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the first partnerships that Gameloft Advertising Solutions signs directly with a DSP, and in the first phase Gameloft Advertising Solutions’ inventory will only be available in mediasmart via private deals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart clients will now have access to a global inventory of more than 8 billion impressions and a reach of 166 million global unique users each month. Adding this premium inventory to mediasmart´s proven capabilities in audience and predictive targeting, gives brands the ability to maximize the reach and effectiveness of their mobile campaigns, while protecting their brand integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With over 21 million daily active users, Gameloft, via Gameloft Advertising Solutions, has complete ownership of its inventory and offers 100% viewability, as well as complete transparency for mediasmart users.” says Cyril Guilleminot, Director for France &amp;amp; Benelux at Gameloft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are thrilled to partner with Mediasmart to allow advertisers and agencies to safely reach their mobile audiences in a transparent and engaging environment with video and display formats.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“mediasmart is a trusted provider to customers in more than 15 countries across EMEA and America, all of whom use our platform in a self-serve mode” says Noelia Amoedo, CEO of mediasmart, “We are dedicated to providing our customers with not only the best mobile technology, but also the best available mobile inventory. This partnership is yet another step in that direction.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding a Workaround for Effective Mobile Measurement</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/finding-a-workaround-for-effective-mobile-measurement" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-02-25:mediasmart-pelican/blog/finding-a-workaround-for-effective-mobile-measurement</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s MWC week, so naturally, the spotlight is firmly planted on mobile and in this piece, mobile measurements. Despite common beliefs, the technology required to measure the return on a mobile ad investment (particularly within apps) is fairly robust nowadays. A wide range of suppliers can now measure any action taken by the user on a mobile device after seeing an ad. And yet, mobile measurement remains a challenge for the industry. Noelia Amoedo (pictured below), CEO, Mediasmart tells ExchangeWire that the standardisation of mobile measurement tools is required for advertisers to keep up with the pace of mobile influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to source accurate measurements comes with the caveat that various technical challenges exist around measuring the ROI that can be directly attributed to a mobile campaign. As is the case with all media types, these technical challenges present themselves when an advertiser is trying to measure attribution across channels. As an industry, we need to look at performance of campaigns across all channels, whilst also considering the influence of each channel over the others, while at the same time, addressing the “if you didn’t measure it didn’t exist” mentality. But this not a challenge that is specific to mobile measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From basic ad viewability to user engagement that justifies ROI, the main challenges to overcome are actually non-technical ones. Whilst the tools exist, often they are not considered “reliable” by the big players. This is largely because the technology required for proper measurement is not used by the vendors that have established themselves as the standard in the digital advertising world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that the majority of measurement tools available are desktop-first solutions compounds the challenge in the current justification of mobile ROI. The technical nuances of the mobile ecosystem and, in particular, of the in-app inventory, mean that desktop orientated tools focused on web have a long way to go to be truly fit-for-purpose. Until they do develop sufficiently, or mobile-first tools become trusted by the agencies and advertisers with the big budgets, mobile investment will continue to lag behind its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the best workaround for now? The obvious way to justify ROI is by measuring conversions, engagement and viewabilty etc., but here’s the main caveat: To accurately measure ROI on a mobile campaign and avoid wasting advertising money on mobile, the first step is to be aware of (and then compensate and account for) some of the issues inherent in measuring with desktop-first solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inaccuracies with current mobile measurement solutions often stem from the difference between desktop and mobile devices. Where advertisers and tracking tool providers are measuring website engagement that results from a mobile advertising campaign, for example, there are a couple of differences that could generate huge measurement inaccuracies and discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cookies and Fingerprinting in Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies don’t work well in the mobile ecosystem. In the mobile advertising world, a customer increasingly clicks on an ad within an app, so the destination URL is not necessarily opened by a browser on the mobile device, but inside the application. The destination URL is opened via a custom browser within the app (or web-view). When the user closes this web-view, he will stay within the app as he navigates through the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One peculiarity of this web-view is that each application is completely isolated from the rest, and also isolated from the browser in the mobile device (i.e “sandboxing”). This is a fundamental aspect of the OS security for Android and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside is that sites that open within applications this way will not be able to read or write persistent cookies. So desktop-first tools will not be able to use cookies to identify whether a user or a visit is new. In some cases in which persistent cookies cannot be written, some tools are designed to use combinations of IP address and user agents in order to track. However, this “fingerprinting approach has a couple of important caveats as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full user agent in mobile devices is not always usable, and often the information taken from the user agent is limited to the model and make. Also, devices such as the Samsung Galaxy and iPhone/iPad present little or no fragmentation when it comes to user agent. Given the success of these brands and models, many clicks may have taken place in devices that have identical user agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP is not often usable either, because on mobile, many devices will share the same IP while they browse on the mobile carrier network, and secondly, most mobile customers use a shared IP model that originated with the old WAP gateways.
In a nutshell, campaigns that have served impressions and generated clicks in web-views within apps, and are tracked with systems that are based on cookies, will not measure users or corresponding visits. Even if those systems have a fallback fingerprinting method in case cookies can’t be used, they will not measure many users or visits that are served in Samsung and iOS devices via 3G connections. The situation would also be similar on iOS for mobile web of course, as third party cookies are prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective mobile ad measurement to justify ROI in a particular campaign is a question of trusting the right technology providers. They do exist, even if they aren’t mobile specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there’s a long way to go until the industry will be able to use these tools in a way that allows commitment to ROI guarantees and viewability standards – and to get there the various industry players need to be aligned. This can only come through standardising technical solutions for the in-app environment, and through industry maturity, as conflicts between advertiser and publisher goals for viewability measurement has shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this chicken-and-egg situation, it’s likely that the demand side is best positioned to take the lead towards a robust standard. After all, it’s the DSPs who are able to measure whether an ad has been viewed or not and to systematically optimise a campaign to place more value on those offered placements more likely to become viewable impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, as an industry we all need to figure out how to approach this alignment so that measurement tools operate in the interests of everyone – and we need to do this soon. With the growing pace of mobile influence, accurate viewability guarantees and ROI measurement will become imperative to the very existence of the mobile advertising industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s clear that both the required technology and industry standards will come together eventually. What remains to be seen is whether the desktop first players step up to the plate to provide this, or whether existing and new mobile specific offerings rise to gain the trust of the advertisers, in the same way as they did for in-app tracking and attribution – and it’s even bet either way.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>When Ad Formats and Mobile Programmatics Collide</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/when-ad-formats-and-mobile-programmatics-collide" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-01-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2016-01-12:mediasmart-pelican/blog/when-ad-formats-and-mobile-programmatics-collide</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of programmatic ad tech has created platforms that can now use first and third party data and artificial intelligence to deliver very sophisticated predictive targeting – enhancing the media buying process to allow marketers to quickly target very specific audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools will fall short of their objectives, of course, if the very foundation of our industry – the ad itself – is not relevant and engaging or is perceived as an invasion or inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it is vital to consider the most appropriate ad format for your campaign. So what are the crucial considerations in choosing the right ad format for a given audience objective, and what are the challenges and benefits of using each format in a programmatic environment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The trusty display ad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional static or animated image based formats of banner and interstitial ads remain key components of most mobile marketing campaigns. These are typically shown inside a web page or app within a page or within closable ad units. Both these formats ensure strong viewability for mobile optimised publishers, and offer a single interaction point to be clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, the same ad units also allow the serving of rich media, offering an immersive experience that allows users to play within the ad unit and interact with multiple calls to action. Used effectively, rich media ads are capable of increasing user engagement and conversion with customizable CTAs, even if they are mostly used because of their ability to boost brand awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, the challenge with using rich media ads was making sure the user experience within the ad unit was not broken due to a fragmented in-app ecosystem and the way in which each ad unit is served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This remains a challenge for those who work with custom rich media ad servers, but it can be overcome by using one of the growing number of mobile-first rich media vendors certified with the programmatic mobile supply sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banner images can also be made even more relevant with the use of personalisation technologies. Imagine, for example banners including dynamic elements that change based on the user’s location. These are ideal for marketers looking to maximise engagement, personalise their communications and increase relevancy to their target audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Advanced ad formats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond traditional display, lie the even more engaging and sophisticated advanced formats of native and video ads, which again, have become increasingly available programmatically, as the mobile programmatic environment matures. These two formats can now also be bought through real time bidding (RTB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Native Ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native inventory arrived with a bang less than two years ago. While publishers have been slow to adopt the format, use of these content-driven ads that match any app’s user experience, is about to reach a tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native ads allow marketing to be more descriptive, with a clear call to action, facilitating more qualified clicks. They are therefore a highly efficient vehicle for generating engagement and conversions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also offer a non-interruptive and high quality ad experience for the end-user, and again, are becoming a compelling option for marketers focusing on building brand awareness, especially as they can now include video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a programmatic environment, native ads offer similar viewability guarantees as image ads, as the creative assets are delivered directly to the SSP, which has full control over how to render them properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the emergence of ad-blocking software, many believe native formats will play an increasingly important role in coming years. Recent standardisation and the ability to offer less intrusive and more personalized ads that work well for both the advertiser and the consumer, will also promote their cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rising importance of and hunger for online video content, use of programmatically available mobile video ads is also expected to grow in 2016, as mobile first supply partners adopt the format and video supply partners extend support to mobile. Programmatic mobile video is delivered to ad exchanges and SSPs via VAST tags, therefore increasing viewing guarantees, as the tags are standardised within the marketplace. They also maximize measurability for the advertiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many see video as key to the evolution of mobile advertising, as it offers greater creative scope, relevancy and engagement levels. It holds strong potential for advertisers looking beyond brand awareness to a direct response, as video formats are becoming more action driven with full screen “end cards” and inclusion of native video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016 is set to be another big year for the development of mobile ad formats. This is timely because the industry needs the ad format ecosystem to evolve to accommodate new measurement and viewability demands and the implications of ad-blocking tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s clear that all formats, whether traditional or advanced, will continue to develop rapidly over the coming years and soon the majority will be supported by the programmatic ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio formats, playable ads and interactive video are just a few examples of what’s to come; and we’re set for exciting times, because as ad formats evolve to become even more relevant and engaging, the algorithms behind them will offer us unprecedented levels of customer insight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart partners with TVTY to maximize multi platform campaign effectiveness</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-partners-with-tvty-to-maximize-multi-platform-campaign-effectiveness" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-10-26:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-partners-with-tvty-to-maximize-multi-platform-campaign-effectiveness</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mediasmart has partnered with TVTY, the moment marketing platform that allows brands to instantly connect online advertising to what’s going on in the offline world. By combining TVTY video fingerprint technology and mediasmart´s mediasmart demand side platform, the partnership allows brands to reach people at the key moments when they reach for their smartphone or tablet to check the web or interact on social media. Ultimately, it will maximize advertising effectiveness and help advertisers achieve stronger results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TVTY monitors every TV ad, in real-time, across over 400 TV channels in 25 countries, using a combination of automated ‘video finger printing’ and human analysis. This allows brands to see exactly which ad is being aired, not an approximation based on a media plan model. Once a designated ad is detected, the TVTY platform triggers a mobile campaign configured on mediasmart. This enables advertisers to boost campaigns in real time at the right moment and across multiple platforms. TVTY can also trigger campaigns based on offline information, such as weather conditions, financial information or live sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are very excited to partner with TVTY and incorporate its innovative technology, to enhance our ongoing effort to help advertisers reach their mobile audiences effectively. With the ubiquity of mobile devices and TVTYs technology, our advertisers can now move a step closer to the goal of creating impact with their target users at exactly the right moment in time”, says Noelia Amoedo, mediasmart CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierre Marechal, Co-founder of TVTY, said: “With consumers bombarded by so much advertising each day and the rising cost of online advertising, it’s more important than ever for brands to be in the moment when it comes to their marketing message. Our partnership with Mediasmart’s mediasmart demand side platform will allow brands to cut through the noise, be relevant and optimise their mobile media spend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ABOUT TVTY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TVTY enables advertisers to synchronize their digital campaigns with offline events in real time (TV shows, commercials, weather/weather forecasts, sporting events, financial triggers, and more). With TVTY, advertisers can ensure that their message reaches the right audience at the right time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With TVTY&amp;#8217;s SaaS Moment Marketing Platform, advertisers pick offline moments, and sync their existing digital campaigns seamlessly. TVTY is already integrated with leading DSPs and ad servers, and is compatible with all digital marketing channels including search, display, video, and social. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TVTY is a VC backed start-up that has offices in New York, London and Paris and operates in more than 20 different countries worldwide. TVTY offers premium advertising solutions to top-tier brands such as McDonald&amp;#8217;s, Coca-Cola, Ford, Samsung, Microsoft, Kia, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read More in &lt;a href="http://www.tvty.tv/"&gt;TVTY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Often Misunderstood Mobile User Privacy Landscape</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-often-misunderstood-mobile-user-privacy-landscape" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-10-20:mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-often-misunderstood-mobile-user-privacy-landscape</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s been a surprising degree of misunderstanding about privacy and tracking of users on mobile recently, from advertisers and consumers alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent MMA panel event I was participating in, saw many of the agencies and advertisers present voicing the opinion that you can’t track user behaviour and preferences on mobile to the same extent as on desktop. There were also many of those present expressing legal concerns over privacy on mobile through the use of location data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many believe tracking on mobile is not possible due to the absence of cookies, but let’s be clear on this. With mobile, users are actually tracked using cookies in mobile web form (although cookies are used in a more restrictive way on mobile), and through Mobile Device Identifiers. Most user engagement actually comes from apps and these native IDs are as accurate, if not more, than their cookie web equivalent. What happens is that often, desktop-first solutions fail to properly cover the in-app environment, which is a very different scenario from mobile tracking not being possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, privacy concerns have revolved around the unique identifiers which can be used to identify individual mobile devices, but these have evolved significantly over time. Previously MAC address, IMEA and Android ID or UDID were used as device IDs. Concerns with their use was widespread, as they were permanent IDs that did not offer users the choice of whether they were tracked or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no longer the case with the new advertising IDs from Microsoft, Apple and Google &amp;#8211; which satisfy both growing consumer privacy concerns and the requirements of advertisers to be able to track their advertising more precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These now give users even more control over their privacy, allowing them initially to decide whether or not to be tracked through these IDs in their phone settings, in a similar way to erasing cookies in your browser on your computer &amp;#8211; but easier. Whereas cookies need to be removed for each browser and through a process that requires multiple non obvious steps, in the app world users have access to just one setting that prevents tracking for all apps with a single one button click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this basis there should be no more concern over using Advertising IDs than there are about using cookies. Despite this, concerns will still remain over location information however, and to a similar degree, such concerns are also misplaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is important to clarify that using the location of a user to serve a campaign can clearly be considered advertising in context, and location as “contextual” information should not raise any concerns around privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of location info should only be a concern when such location is a) directly stored with a user profile, even if that user is not identified by personal information and b) stored in ‘exact form’. In this case algorithms could, in theory, be used to determine where a user lives based on their behavioral patterns, and this information could of course be used to identify that individual. Guidelines such as those set down by the NAI (Network Advertising Initiative) refer to the correct use of location in advertising involving locating down to two decimal points, rather than storing exact user locations to be used as part of a specific user profile. Any advertiser that wants to put any privacy concerns at ease, should demand his providers are following such guidelines if they store user location history, but they should not simply dismiss the use of location information over legal concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brands and advertisers obviously understand the negative impact from intrusive marketing, and most are keen to ensure that privacy is respected. The Digital Advertising Alliance recently enforced its Principles in the Mobile Environment (DAA Mobile Guidance) for instance, which includes new guidance specific to mobile, such as across-app data, precise location data and personal directory data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate advertising goal, of course, is to ensure users receive the kind of ads that are directly relevant to them, at the location and time they’ll be most receptive. This will mean optimising campaigns remains central to the mobile privacy and tracking debate. Using the right tools and technologies will also help provide mobile ads which offer value and make users more likely to exercise their right to accept them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Mobile Viewability Enigma</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-mobile-viewability-enigma" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-08-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-08-26:mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-mobile-viewability-enigma</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mobile viewability continues to spark debate as mobile media buying becomes increasingly programmatic and both media buyers and sellers clamour for guarantees and standards. Either side are companies claiming viewability on mobile is not an issue and those who strongly argue it is, and data has only confused the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent study stated mobile viewability is lower than 50 per cent, whilst another suggests ad placements sized for mobile are more viewable than desktop-specific creative for almost all display ad formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is we’re not comparing like with like by examining “mobile” in this generic way, and hence the disparate results. After all, the probability that ads served are viewed or not depends largely on the type of inventory we are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, with studies comparing ads served on non-mobile-optimised websites, you would expect ad visibility to be lower when those sites are consumed on mobile devices, versus when they are consumed on desktop. Browsing here involves fast scrolling, swiping and zooming to read content, causing users to miss ads placed further down a page, published within a shrunken format out of the readers view, or those that haven’t even had a chance to load before zooming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads placed within mobile optimised content don’t suffer this, and the more in-app inventory weight in a mobile campaign, the stronger its viewability will be. After all, in-app ads are either full screen or built to fix in a certain screen position. So with comparisons that only account for optimised websites and in-app inventory on mobile, versus websites consumed on desktops, it stands to reason that ad viewability would be higher on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that most viewability issues stem from the mobile web, and specifically, non-optimised inventory, ads on mobile are intrinsically less problematic than on desktop &amp;#8211; and especially with in-app, where the experience is vastly different to the web experience. With in-app inventory, which accounts for the majority of available inventory currently, viewability is a relatively a minor concern. Perhaps because of this, certain supply providers in the mobile world have already started offering “viewability guarantees”, and charging only for impressions that have been viewed by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mobile visibility argument is a largely subjective one to this point, but regardless of its perceived level of importance, its measurement is becoming vital. Any guarantees provided by publishers, exchanges and supply side players will be insufficient for those advertisers concerned with viewability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They expect unbiased tools provided by independent players to measure and track viewability across channels. And this is where the technical nuances of the mobile ecosystem and, in particular, of the in-app inventory, come into play once again. Viewability tools need to measure across each of the many compatible software development kits (SDK’s) of supply partners that are serving the ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst agencies have traditionally trusted existing third parties to do this, most of these have used generic web measurement tools that haven’t sufficiently evolved to accurately track in this mobile environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only with the right technology and assurances in place that we can establish industry agreement and trust on viewability standards and commit to in app guarantees. The majority of supply side players will need to offer this for full confidence, and ultimately we’ll need them to be validated by an independent third party viewability measurement organization or dedicated vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Media Ratings Council (MRC) is making progress here, but its viewable impressions guidance still relates largely to the desktop experience. Mobile is a much more complex ecosystem and many see the issue with viewability as a technical one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the growing pace of mobile influence, accurate viewability, measurement and guarantees will become imperative to the mobile advertising industry. What remains to be seen is whether the desktop first players step up to the plate to provide this, or whether existing and new mobile specific offerings rise to gain the trust of the advertisers, in the same way as they did for in-app tracking and attribution. Either way, a mobile standard is coming soon – and it can’t come soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Optimise, Track and Test in a Mobile First World</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/optimise-track-and-test-in-a-mobile-first-world" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-06-11:mediasmart-pelican/blog/optimise-track-and-test-in-a-mobile-first-world</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Certain market sectors now acknowledge that a ‘mobile first’ strategy is essential to their commercial futures. We’ve come a long way since the days when Uber was one of a handful of mobile-first businesses, and household names, such as Argos, are now committed to entirely mobile focused business models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many large customer focused enterprises are yet to jump on board however, and an alarming number have still not optimised their core web presence for mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is this a concern? The fastest-growing part of the internet market is display advertising, which is forecast to surge 20% this year to £2.7bn. &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/media/2014/dec/01/gadget-obsessed-uk-top-digital-advertising-spend"&gt;39% of that is mobile display advertising&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, at the same time, a recent IAB study suggests that 10% of the top 250 UK brands are running mobile display campaigns without an optimised site or a mobile application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimisation is clearly the first objective here. When users interact with your ad on a mobile device, they need to have the best possible experience &amp;#8211; interacting with rich media that adapts to the screen and works well, or with a mobile optimised landing page. This must be a seamless and user-friendly experience, regardless of whether the ad is independent or part of a larger mobile optimised site or mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you may have encouraged a user who is interested in your brand to a new page or site. If they need to pinch or tap the screen to clearly read the text or navigate in an overly cumbersome way, your ad becomes counter productive and the bad experience will also be associated with your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your primary consideration for your mobile presence must be designing this user experience for ease of use, whether this is achieved via a mobile site, a native app or both. The next key steps are testing and tracking to ensure a better understanding of your customer. This involves testing thoroughly to ensure your site works perfectly on all devices and operating systems, and then tracking for data analysis, which accounts for the user journey from desktop to tablet and smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to make fully effective use of your mobile apps, make sure you don’t keep them in silos, from a data perspective; ideally, you should know your user independently of how he or she is interacting with your service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proper optimised design, testing and tracking also applies to your ads, and you should always consider testing a variety of creatives. Once you have your creative assets in place, personalise them and the post-click experience thoroughly, using your own First Party Data wherever you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to tracking, you should use advertising platforms that gather and share data extensively &amp;#8211; ensuring all campaign KPIs are tracked per advertising channel and that they gather as much information as possible about the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also important that you share back with these advertising platforms in order to optimise; posting back results to advertising channels for optimisation (ideally in real time) and sharing First Party data, will also help them optimise the media buying process – working back to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately however, brands and marketers must track as much as possible, whilst remaining realistic. Tracking and attribution systems can’t capture absolutely everything, and if you could only work with mediums where everything can be precisely measured, broadcast advertising would cease to exist!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s clear is that nowadays, with mobile devices having surpassed desktops and laptops as the gateway to the internet, it is essential to optimise for mobile first, and then work back to the “fixed” experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days when an optimised mobile experience was a ‘nice to have’ afterthought – and for advertisers and end users alike, that is a very positive state of affairs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>tenthavenue selects mediasmart as its Demand Side Platform</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/tenthavenue-selects-mediasmart-as-its-demand-side-platform" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-05-20:mediasmart-pelican/blog/tenthavenue-selects-mediasmart-as-its-demand-side-platform</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;tenthavenue &amp;#8211; a WPP company &amp;#8211; has selected mediasmart as the technology provider to help streamline its programmatic media buying operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart&amp;#8216;s mobile-first demand side platform – will be used in a self-serve mode, empowering tenthavenue teams to programmatically buy media using the direct agreements tenthavenue holds with media owners, and within the open marketplace via Real Time Bidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IAB (Internet Advertising Bureau) UK forecasted last August that by 2017, between 60% and 75% of all digital advertising will be traded programmatically. Comparing mobile versus desktop, mobile already drives a larger percentage of media investment through some form of programmatic technology today (RTB or Direct). Mobile inventory, particularly in-app, is also growing at a much faster pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The partnership with a mobile-first technology provider, will help to further position tenthavenue as a leading programmatic player and enable tenthavenue&amp;#8217;s advertisers to engage with their audiences more effectively than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We are thrilled to partner with tenthavenue, a partner that not only understands the paradigm change that programmatic and the growth of mobile have meant for the digital advertising industry, but which plans to take advantage of it to deliver more value to advertisers&amp;#8221;, Noelia Amoedo, CEO of mediasmart, said. &amp;#8220;We bring our technology to this partnership in addition to our experience and mobile expertise&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This partnership fits perfectly with our personalized content distribution strategy as it contributes directly to three tenthavenue pillars: data, technology and media. Our team thoroughly evaluated eight demand side platforms, and we are confident mediasmart is the best choice”, Ludovic Chayriguès, tenthavenue France COO, explains. “Our goal is to help our clients get the most out of their digital and out-of-home strategies, with a strong focus on mobile. This strategic partnership brings us one step closer in that direction&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Ensuring Native Ads Provide Real Value to Consumers</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/ensuring-native-ads-provide-real-value-to-consumers" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-05-01:mediasmart-pelican/blog/ensuring-native-ads-provide-real-value-to-consumers</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The rise of the native ad remains one of the hottest topics in digital media and there is growing acknowledgement of its ability to build trust and engagement with current and prospective customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brands love the way native advertising makes them appear to be part of the conversation through a less intrusive user experience that matches their own personality. But, as the line between content and advertising blurs further, native ads have also been the subject of bad press and openly accused of deceiving end-users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we define native advertising as paid advertising that is consistent with a particular page content, design and platform behaviour, the very first successful examples of native advertising were actually early SEM (search engine optimisation) deliveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays however, there is a confusing variety of so-called “native ads”. &lt;a href="http://www.iab.net/media/file/IABNativeAdvertisingPlaybook.pdf"&gt;A recent whitepaper from the IAB&lt;/a&gt; aims to eliminate confusion by classifying them into six specific categories (with well known examples) and marketplace considerations. But put simply, where display advertising is concerned, we should differentiate between those native ads that include ‘sponsored’ content, and those that don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored content ads include news-format content in publications or social networks, and these face most of the moral arguments about the dividing line between news or user generated content and advertising. These types of ads usually span across mobile and desktop properties &amp;#8211; think of the Sponsored Tweets in Twitter, sponsored posts in Facebook or BuzzFeed&amp;#8217;s news – for these to avoid being “deceptive”, publications need to go the extra mile to ensure the quality of the content offers value, and always ensure that the ads can be easily identified as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain native ads commonly used by mobile publishers &amp;#8211; normally apps &amp;#8211; are not based on content per se, they simply blend with the look and feel of the mobile app where they reside. This type of native ad has been pioneered by certain social networks, communication apps and news aggregators and include, for example, the “app promotion” ads you see in your Facebook app. These are the ads that, having so far been used mostly for direct marketing campaigns, are at their best against traditional banner ads on the small screen format of mobile devices; and they provide notable advantages to consumers. They’re not intrusive and when consumers do choose to interact with them, their interaction is far more qualified and less prone to errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective ‘best practice’ native ads contain a lot of information about the product or service they offer and a clear ‘call to action’ button, minimising the chance of prospects clicking on ads by mistake, and therefore significantly reducing the rate of unintentional clicks typically associated with banners, whilst improving the user experience. The interactions they encourage are more qualified, the ads are less intrusive and there’s obvious transparency on what is advertising and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This more qualified interaction on the native ad experience generates much higher conversion rates: in our campaigns we´ve registered Click Through Rates (CTRs) that were up to 50% higher in native ads than in standard banners. Performance has also been even better when it comes to conversion rates &amp;#8211; measuring up to 10 times higher than traditional banner ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returns like this are likely to improve further as native ads become even more contextual (with an ad inviting you to a Spotify trial, as you’re reading a music article, for example). There’s also huge latent potential to combine this sort of context with creativity in native advertising of course. As audiences get used to these new formats, the line between what is advertising and what is not will become increasingly obvious to them, just as today it is obvious which of the Search results are sponsored and which ones are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to the question “are native ads good for consumers?” I would say a resounding “yes”, provided best practises are followed”. But I would answer with an even louder “yes” when we refer to the “non-content” native ads the industry has been using so far within mobile apps, due to the numerous advantages they offer over traditional banners on a smaller screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is by embracing best practises in this way that brands and publishers can seize the opportunity to move with the times and engage with audiences on both a valuable and commercially beneficial basis.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Programmatic: An Opportunity, not a Threat</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/programmatic-an-opportunity-not-a-threat" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-03-05:mediasmart-pelican/blog/programmatic-an-opportunity-not-a-threat</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Media buying has been dramatically transformed by programmatic practices. Current technologies allow marketers to engage directly with their target audience in a more efficient way than ever. However, some professionals still see programmatic as a kind of threat that will replace human knowledge and lead to numerous job losses. This is not the case. The most knowledgeable specialists are fully aware that programmatic media buying is so powerful that the sooner they incorporate it, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2017, programmatic is expected to be the only way that media is bought. In the most advanced markets, such as those operating in the US, programmatic already represents almost 50% of total display ad investment (10 billion dollars), according to eMarketer figures. It is also expected to grow to up to 63% of the total $20 billion investment by 2016. The growth forecasts are even more impressive for mobile, where inventory has traditionally been far more aggregated: In 2016 programmatic will form 70% of the $14.15 billion invested in digital display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The huge potential of this new buying method has not always been clear for the majority of marketers and publishers. On mobile, the first to take advantage of programmatic media buying, in the form of Real Time Bidding in open marketplaces, were a) advertisers looking for direct response and b) long tail apps, or apps that had a lot of traffic but were lacking a strong brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big brands, both on the advertising and publishing side, avoided programmatic, because they felt the open marketplace didn’t protect the value of their brands: advertisers were not confident in associating with a publisher brand that was compatible with theirs and publishers thought the premium nature of their brand would be wasted in the open marketplace, and actually cannibalise their existing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the attitude of big brands is now changing thanks to Programmatic Direct, which brings together the best of both worlds. Advertisers and publishers can now maintain those direct relationships that offer the control and accountability that is so treasured in the traditional media buying world &amp;#8211; and ensure they associate with the brands they truly want to engage with. At the same time, by buying programmatically they can buy audiences effectively and optimise in real time, making buying decisions impression by impression and user by user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe Programmatic Direct will finally win premium publishers and brands over to the programmatic cause, but there is still some resistance to overcome. This is especially the case on the agency side, where some still believe that programmatic means losing the human touch with algorithms taking over from professional instinct and recommendations, leading to the extinction of media planners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is, as some agencies already understand, that programmatic is there to boost media planners’ capabilities. It actually empowers them and super charges their ability to build and control a campaign (and the data behind it) at a far more granular level. Where previously they were bulk buying media based on aggregated reports from various Excel spreadsheets, they can now have a direct view on the media, build and manage their own campaigns and obtain a detailed view on campaign and ad optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clever programmatic algorithms mean this new detailed level of perspective can also be analysed on a real time basis and across many more variables than a human with an excel sheet could effectively process, allowing campaigns to be automatically optimised ‘on-the-go’. But the planner is still extremely important, to oversee what algorithms do and tweak campaigns on a regular basis based on the targeting that is working most effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with the functionality to plan campaigns on an individual ‘per impression’ basis – planners can now learn about their audiences and plan smarter campaigns, like specific campaigns for new customers alongside different offers for dormant or legacy customers, for example, or campaigns segmented to users that planners know have shown certain previous behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supercharged in this way, planners &amp;#8211; and the agencies they work for &amp;#8211; can bring far more value to advertisers. Media planners will certainly have to evolve to command all the tools and data at their disposal in this new super-charged state, but there is enormous scope for them in the new programmatic paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, those companies and professionals that understand this new win-win buying paradigm, and consider it as an opportunity rather than a threat, will position themselves as the biggest and most effective players of the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart announces strategic partnership with Experian Marketing Services</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-experiang-marketing-services-enter-a-strategic-partnership-2" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2015-02-19:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-and-experiang-marketing-services-enter-a-strategic-partnership-2</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mediasmart and Experian Marketing Services, a global provider of integrated consumer insight, targeting, data quality and cross-channel marketing, are entering a strategic partnership that brings together the benefits of mediasmart, with the accuracy and scale of Experian’s cross-channel audience data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the partnership, mediasmart customers will have access to Experian’s Mosaic, its comprehensive cross-channel consumer classification, built for today&amp;#8217;s hyper-connected world. Using new data and analytical methods, brands get access to deeper insights on consumer lifestyles and behaviour to make more informed media buying decisions in real time. Mosaic gives a pin-sharp picture of today&amp;#8217;s consumer, reflecting the latest consumer and societal trends. Over 850 million pieces of information across 450 different data points are condensed using the latest analytical techniques to identify 15 summary groups and 66 detailed types that are easy to interpret and understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to partner with Experian Marketing Services to unlock the power of audience-based targeting for in-app mobile advertising at scale. Our goal is to take advantage of technology to enable advertisers to connect with their target audience: those really interested in their product or service. Partnering with Experian is one more step in our continuous effort to bring the most advanced solutions to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The partnership delivers both on industry and consumer needs, providing intelligent interactions when, where and how they matter most to the consumer. Experian is committed to developing and investing in a strategic partner network that offers clients end-to-end, cross-channel digital advertising service. And mediasmart’s consistent, proven track record of innovation in mobile and advertising technology makes the company an ideal partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experian Mosaic data is immediately available in the UK and Spain. Contact sales@mediasmart.mobi if you want more information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Measuring Post-Click Events: Best Practice Against “Fat-Finger Syndrome”</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/measuring-post-click-events-best-practice-against-fat-finger-syndrome" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-12-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-12-17:mediasmart-pelican/blog/measuring-post-click-events-best-practice-against-fat-finger-syndrome</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mobile marketing is a medium that is still considered to be quite new in comparison to more traditional mediums like the more established TV and online. As such, it is normal to feel some uncertainty or trepidation when marketers choose to invest in mobile marketing. The market’s lack of maturity means that there is a real coexistence of efficient and trusted solutions alongside some others which may be less proven or less appropriate to the reality of the mobile ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, a change of perspective is required to fully understand much of the mobile space; from the opportunities that the new formats present, to the pricing models that can provide a better fit for specific requirements and budgets. It is not appropriate to simply imitate models that have been applied in the online environment, because browsing the Internet from a mobile device is a totally different experience. In this context, the “fat-finger syndrome” &amp;#8211; a phenomenon that we´ve come to recognise within the mobile advertising space &amp;#8211; should be taken into consideration: Often users click on banners when they have absolutely no intention of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies conducted over the last two years have claimed that up to 40 per cent of mobile ad clicks are either fraudulent or accidental, and have suggested that more than half of those are a result of fat finger syndrome. Another study found that just 12 per cent of smartphone users ever click on an advert intentionally and only 6 per cent actually go on to purchase following the interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has been written about this “syndrome”, and often to the detriment of mobile advertising as a whole. It is true that it describes a reality that needs to be taken into account when we talk about mobile advertising, but the good news is that while this “syndrome” is maximised by the use of media buying technologies that just optimise CTRs, it also can be minimised by implementing the appropriate technology instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have the capability to use technology, not only to measure impressions and clicks, but also to learn about user behavior with a more holistic approach. We can use advertising formats that require a “double click” or that include a distinct call to action, such as native ads, which reduce the fat finger errors. And, above all, we can measure what users do after they interact with banner adverts, and work with programmatic media buying platforms which use algorithms to take into account that all-important post-click behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are technology platforms today, like mediasmart, that can track accurately almost any post-click event: from calls to a call center, to visits or registrations in a website, or installs and use of apps, etc. If a programmatic platform buys media in real time, impression by impression, depending on the probability each impression has of turning into a post-click interaction, by definition, it will not buy those impressions that generated non-intended clicks, simply because these clicks will rarely be followed by any interaction other than the closing of the ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, we have seen campaigns with an airline driving flight ticket purchases though an app, or campaigns where a car manufacturer drives complete video views by unique users, in which certain publishers have been naturally “selected out” by the media buying algorithm due to low performance, in spite of very good CTRs. This is a clear indication of publishers or advertising formats with a high rate of unintentional clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the fat finger syndrome is a real issue, particularly in the mobile advertising world, and especially for platforms that only optimise CTR &amp;#8211; which, precisely because of this syndrome should not be the sole indicator of success for any campaign. But the industry has now progressed. It is now a problem that can be minimised as much as to make it almost insignificant if you use the appropriate technology, or work with providers with the proper technology.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart reinvents the banner with cinematic 3D effects</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-reinvents-the-banner-with-cinematic-3d-effects" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-10-24:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-reinvents-the-banner-with-cinematic-3d-effects</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mediasmart, a company that optimizes mobile media buying with its leading mobile DSP (Demand Side Platform), has launched a revolutionary format with cinematic 3D effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new banner offers a unique opportunity to increase awareness and performance, helping brands get noticed, especially now that we face the Christmas season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing brand recognition and user engagement are some of the main benefits of the new format. It also helps achieve higher CTR (Click-through rate) ratios compared to traditional banner and, therefore, it delivers higher conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart launches this advanced solution in partnership with with Full Moon Advertising, and it is exclusive provider of this technology in the mobile space in Spain and UK. With the 1.0 version, now available, advertisers can choose almost one hundred three-dimensions animations with different themes: from a paper plain to the water fill effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With the exponential rise of mobile campaigns, we are consuming more and more brands ‘on-the-run’ so, this is a huge opportunity for our clients to differentiate themselves,” says Julio Aguayo, International Business Development at mediasmart. “With Christmas right around the corner, this really is the perfect time to launch this revolutionary format and see what it can do for branding and CTR. As mobile consumption increases and devices get better resolution, it is really exciting to see how mobile campaigns evolve”, he points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to launch this revolutionary format with a company like mediasmart, an expert making mobile advertising more efficient. Its strong reputation and huge knowledge make it the partner of choice to innovate in this industry”, explains Full Moon Adversting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Constant Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of cinematic 3D effects follows mediasmart strategy of delivering cutting-edge solutions to its clients. Along this line, the company has recently introduced the ability to programmatically buy native ads, as well as dynamic banners that change according to user’s geographic location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We strive to offer our clients the best service and the best advertising solutions, committing to results and real effectiveness, beyond a simple number of clicks or impressions. Mediasmart´s goal is to take advantage of technology to let advertisers connect with their target audience: those really interested in their product or service” Noelia Amoedo, CEO of mediasmart, explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The mix of these new and attractive formats with the effectiveness of mediasmart, our proprietary DSP platform designed for mobile programmatic buying, is the perfect combination for success in mobile marketing and makes mediasmart the best option for any brand that wants to connect with their audience on mobile devices” she highlights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Promoting Mobile Apps in the New World</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/promoting-mobile-apps-in-the-new-world" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-10-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-10-15:mediasmart-pelican/blog/promoting-mobile-apps-in-the-new-world</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The mobile app market is reported to be valued in excess of €17.5 billion, according to the latest report by the European Commission, ‘Sizing EU App Economy’. The report also highlights the sector as one of the fields with the highest potential for growth and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This market, which didn&amp;#8217;t exist until six years ago, has not only grown rapidly, but it has evolved in a particular way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its first stage, the popularity and the volume of downloads was the main goal of the developer. Today, with mass adoption and huge download numbers (more than 1 million apps available on iOS and Android) engagement and return on investment (ROI) have become more important. In fact Apple now aims to have app rankings reflect more qualitative parameters, looking beyond download numbers, and factoring in user retention and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smartest investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With commercial returns increasingly lucrative, and more and more competition, it is key to understand how to promote mobile apps effectively. Attracting new users is no longer down to being well positioned in stores rankings alone (iTunes App Stores, Google Play, Windows Play, etc.). Of course, it is important to cover all the optimisation basics inside the store, but it is as important to invest in mobile marketing to promote the app outside of the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaign success is often linked to setting up clear objectives from the get-go, and working with providers that can best align with those. In order to achieve that, advertisers have traditionally worked on a Cost Per Install (CPI) basis – which would be effective if the number of downloads is the only goal. It is important to be aware, however, that these CPI models often rely on incentivised downloads, attracting users who download the app to get some other incentive, and are not likely to interact and remain active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you care about users interacting with your app, you need to go one step further. Today it is possible to use tools that measure engagement with the app, therefore avoiding those ‘low quality users’. With that, it makes sense for the Cost Per Engagement to be the main KPI to determine campaign success, instead of the Cost per Install, where the advertiser defines what ‘engagement’ means. For example, an airline might define engagement through flight searches, reservations or actual ticket purchases, while a gaming app may choose the purchase of virtual goods within a game as the key measure. This is ultimately more valuable as it allows for new strategies and campaigns to be completely aligned with the advertisers goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;App Marketing in 3 Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Metrics and Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting to promote any app, you need to establish clear KPIs to measure campaign success. To measure these indicators effectively, you need to insert tracking tools into the app, whether they are from a specific channel or from a specialised tracking provider who can measure in different channels. These tools not only allow the advertiser to measure, but they should also inform the advertising channel in real time, so that they can optimise their ad serving/media buying processes toward the same goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. New User Acquisition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To capture new users it is best to work with providers who can maximise the objectives of the campaign, and not just provide volume in terms of installs. There are programmatic buying platforms that can measure retention levels, engagement and interaction, and then use this information in real time, to make media buying decisions based on predictive targeting, improving the results of the campaigns as they go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Loyalty and Retargeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising campaigns don&amp;#8217;t need to be limited to new user acquisition. The same channels can be used to generate loyalty among existing users. Not every provider can support this kind of campaign, but those able will allow advertisers to create personalised messages to different profiles of users, and to measure the return on investment of each impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executing mobile advertising effectively, combined with the proper optimisation within the app stores, is the key to getting the visibility that any app needs. Of course, all of this only makes sense when the app brings value to its users and it is of good quality, but this doesn´t rely on advertising, does it?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Using Geolocation to your Advantage</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/using-geolocation-to-your-advantage" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-09-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-09-04:mediasmart-pelican/blog/using-geolocation-to-your-advantage</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since its introduction to the advertising industry, geolocation has been quite the buzzword, perceived as one of the main advantages of mobile devices compared to PCs for advertisers. One of the mobile marketing opportunities that brands can take advantage of is to use geolocation technology to reach users with timely messages on their own devices. The ultimate objective is to drive customers to the brand where sales can be closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, accurate geolocation has been slow to take off. There are some key things that have coincided to make it more successful, at scale now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The rise of apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of mobile web, location based information was not something easily or regularly shared. The increased use of mobile apps and an increase in the number of apps that use location information to operate (e.g. local restaurants) has resulted in users becoming more comfortable and more willing to share that detail. It is now much easier for users to enable/disable location sharing as well, often with just one click, and as users feel more comfortable doing so geolocated advertising inventory has significantly increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real-time Bidding (RTB)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real time marketplaces have resulted in greater aggregation of different types of inventory, with a few ad exchanges being the gateway to most in-app ad inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these two drivers, it’s now possible to launch geolocation-based campaigns with big enough reach and greater advertising effectiveness. Users can now naturally receive advertising campaigns that take into consideration their location, while browsing through apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why geolocation?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using geolocation on a mobile advertising campaign may or may not make sense depending on the goals of the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some examples of how geolocation can be used effectively:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Drive traffic to physical locations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the advantages of geolocation is that advertisers with a physical presence can limit their campaign to the geographic area close to their points of sale, with the goal to drive traffic to their stores. Let’s imagine an advertiser has a certain special offer in its stores. Geolocation can impact only users located within a few hundred meters of the stores, and, if the user clicks on the banner, it will open up a map with directions to the closest location and a discount coupon that can be redeemed in the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Customise the message according to the location:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to adapt the advertising campaign to the user’s location in order to maximise the conversion rate. For example, if a user is physically close to the advertiser’s point of sale, (s)he will be shown an in-store offer and directions to the store. If the user isn’t close to the store, (s)he will be shown a generic offer linking to the web, the mobile app or a call centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Reaching your target audience based on their location:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to use geolocated campaigns to reach an audience whose interests have been made clear based on the places they frequent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two possible types of campaigns of this sort:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaigns based on static locations, also called geofenced campaigns. Imagine, for example, how advertisers in the travel industry may want to run campaigns around airports or train stations. These campaigns will only be seen by users physically present at those locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaigns based on dynamic location, that is, campaigns targeted to users whose behavioural profiles have been created based on their geolocated movements. Imagine a campaign targeted to those users that frequently visit airports, who can be profiled as frequent travellers, but that can be seen in any location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For marketers who are ahead of the geolocation curve, there are many reasons to plan and implement a solid location-based mobile marketing strategy — if they don’t, they risk losing market share to mobile-savvy competitors.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mediasmart Mobile innovates again by launching native ads</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-mobile-innovates-again-by-launching-native-ads" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-07-15:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-mobile-innovates-again-by-launching-native-ads</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mediasmart Mobile, a leading mobile DSP (Demand Side Platform), today announced the availability of a new service to programmatically buy native formats within mobile applications. These advertising formats naturally flow with the content of the application in which they are served, so that the content and layout of each ad is different depending on the publisher, and even on the particular section within the publisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native formats have proven a lot more efficient than traditional banners or interstitials in generating engagement. In early campaigns mediasmart registered Click Through Rates (CTRs) that were up to 50% higher. But performance has been even better when it comes to conversion rates, which mediasmart has measured to be up to 10 times superior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is due not only to native ads being more noticeable, but also because they offer more information about the product/service being advertised inside the ad format itself, such as a description, images and a call to action. It is only logical that the clicks they generate are a lot more qualified. These formats are the perfect complement to mediasmart’s predictive targeting algorithms and maximisie the efficiency of campaigns that have a clear call to action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The format of the future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In markets such as the United States the so called native formats already represent $3.1 billion in 2013 and are expected to grow up to $5 billion by 2017, growing to represent 42.2% of total social ad spending, according to forecasts by Bia Kelsey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growth is fueled by perceived effectiveness and increased use of social media, content portals, news properties, video sharing sites and streaming services on smartphones and tablets, according to the new eMarketer report &amp;#8220;Native Advertising: Difficult to Define, but Definitely Growing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mobile advertising company Mediasmart Mobile expands to UK</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-advertising-company-mediasmart-mobile-expands-to-uk" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-06-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-06-11:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-advertising-company-mediasmart-mobile-expands-to-uk</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mediasmart Mobile, a leading mobile RTB platform, today announced the opening of a new London office. Launched in 2012, mediasmart aims to build on their current success as one of the first movers in the European and Latin American markets. The British office will serve London based companies for local, European and worldwide campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart&amp;#8217;s office in London will be headed by Mel Likimani. Mel Likimani has more than 14 years digital advertising experience having worked in companies like Audiencielinx, as Managing Director, Adconion as Sales Director, and Buongiorno as Advertising Sales Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mel Likimani comments that “mediasmart is a company with huge potential in the European market and especially in the UK. As one of the early entrants into the Mobile RTB space our bidding process and optimisation algorithm has been fine tuned to the particular nuances found within mobile. With mobile now established as one of the fastest growing areas in the advertising industry, our mission is to deliver positive results to both performance and brand led campaigns coupled with best-in-market client services and data and analytics integration”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noelia Amoedo, mediasmart’s CEO explains, “I am delighted to welcome Mel to our management team. Given his skills and experience to date, he will be critical to helping us deliver on mediasmart’s international expansion plans, and I have no doubt he will position the company as a key player in the UK mobile advertising market”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart is a technology start-up focused on optimising the media buying process in mobile (both on smartphones and tablets). Thanks to mediasmart, its proprietary DSP (Demand Side Platform) technology, mediasmart maximises advertising effectiveness for agencies and advertisers. mediasmart is a self-learning platform that optimises the media buying process on RTB by using predictive targeting, audience tagging and retargeting, impacting users more whenever the probabilities of generating engagement with a given campaign are higher. For advertisers, this translates into campaigns whose performance continuously improves with time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mobile Vs. PC - Why The Convergence Of Mobile And Digital isn't A Reality</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-vs-pc-why-the-convergence-of-mobile-and-digital-isnt-a-reality" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-06-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-06-05:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-vs-pc-why-the-convergence-of-mobile-and-digital-isnt-a-reality</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mobile has quickly become the darling of the advertising world. In an age where people take their smartphone with them everywhere, advertisers know how important mobile screen time is to engaging, retaining and attracting customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, advertisers also know that in a multiscreen, multidevice world, to place all their eggs in the proverbial mobile basket would be folly. To move customers along the decision-making process, they have to have all screens covered. Which is why it’s so important that mobile and other digital channels play nicely together. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this longed for convergence of the mobile and digital worlds is yet to happen. There are some good reasons for this, the main one being that mobile includes the app ecosystem, and Web and apps are fundamentally different. There are some obvious points, like cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, on the Web, advertisers rely heavily on cookies in order to understand consumer behaviour and tailor their ads to be more relevant and contextual. Yet in the app world, it simply isn&amp;#8217;t possible to work with cookies; a different tracking and attribution model is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also more complexity in the app ecosystem. Let&amp;#8217;s say you implement a Web campaign; the chances are that an advertiser would look to deliver it via a browser and would ensure that it has the big four &amp;#8212; Firefox, Chrome, Safari and Internet Explorer. The campaign can be delivered across all of these browsers with just a few tweaks. Yet in the world of apps, ads and often landing pages are accessed within an application, not in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires different technology and exactly which is determined not only by the ad exchange/network being used by the publisher, but also by the operating system. A user experience that works like a dream on the Web will often be broken if just replicated in the mobile world, given many different variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few examples, but they serve to demonstrate that the real reason that mobile and digital are struggling to converge is complexity. The app ecosystem is different and more complicated. Replicating technologies from the digital world isn&amp;#8217;t always possible or effective. Companies that realize that quickly, usually mobile-first companies, are at an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If advertisers want to effectively crack the mobility nut, they can&amp;#8217;t just simply treat it as an add-on to digital. According to Nielsen, apps now account for 89%of all media time in mobile versus just 11% on the mobile Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sideline the application ecosystem, you are alienating at best &amp;#8212; ignoring at worst &amp;#8212; a huge captive audience. Such explosive and sustained growth in app traffic is what has made mobile such a strategic cornerstone for how advertisers ensure that their marketing campaigns deliver tangible bottom line growth to their business. That isn&amp;#8217;t just my opinion. It has become a platform of such importance that it is only in recent quarters, when Facebook has been able demonstrate that it has a sustainable strategy for mobile and can monetise it as a platform, that its share price has started to recover after a shocking start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile is the future, but for sales growth it has to be integrated with the digital world. The two cannot operate in isolation. There will be consolidation within the market, largely driven by the needs and demands of advertisers. Yet industry watchers assume it will be the digital world that will extend into mobile. I always find this assumption surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile is so much more complex, handling multiple formats, rendering technologies, tracking tools and both Web and app platforms. The skills mastered in the mobile world are much more transferable, and arguably more valuable, than vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s to stop the mobile experts acquiring the digital ones? Convergence is coming, and I think for some it will be a surprise to see who is leading the charge.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart launches new ad format to adapt artwork according to geolocation</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-new-ad-format-to-adapt-artwork-according-to-geolocation" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-05-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-05-18:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-new-ad-format-to-adapt-artwork-according-to-geolocation</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mediasmart, a technology company specialising in the optimisation of mobile advertising, has launched a new system able to serve dynamic creative artwork, which shifts according to a specific user’s location. As a result, the consumer receives the exact information of the nearest point of sale, without ever needing to click the banner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first campaign built with this new format has already been launched with a beer brand, but the system offers huge benefits for all advertisers. In this case, the brand used a common creative artwork and kept a blank on the image so mediasmart’s ad server overlapped the dynamic information. However, this new format allows advertisers to use any kind of personalisation: from different artworks to elements like images, maps, phone numbers, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new format aims to maximise the benefits of geolocation, one of the biggest advantages of mobile marketing. Thanks to its unique platform mediasmart, advertisers can merge the digital and physical worlds, by getting the most from mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our mission at mediasmart is to maximise users’ engagement with our clients’ campaigns”, explains Noelia Amoedo CEO of mediasmart. “Offering new formats personalised for each user is one more step in that sense. We face an increasing demand of advertisers aiming to reach their audience in specific geographic areas and this new format allows them to connect with people in a more effective way”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gelocation, key for mobile marketing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile marketing is an advertising format which continues to have a high growth potential. In 2013 advertising spend in mobile marketing reached 18.16 million dollars, according to eMarketer, which predicts a growth of 62.1% this year. Geolocation, a unique part of this, is one of the key factors that will drive this development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geolocation offers great benefits in different scenarios, but it should be considered as a key element in three situations: when an advertiser aims to drive traffic to a physical place, because campaigns can be limited to a specific area optimising budget; when the goal is to reach a target group and their interests are linked to a physical location (i.e. travel offers in airports); or to deliver different messages depending on where our audience is located (i.e. showing address and offers near the point of sale and aiming to download the app when there’s no shop around).&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Geolocation will be key for brands and advertisers in 2014</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/geolocation-will-be-key-for-brands-and-advertisers-in-2014" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2014-02-19:mediasmart-pelican/blog/geolocation-will-be-key-for-brands-and-advertisers-in-2014</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mediasmart successfully runs geolocation-based campaigns for multiple clients such as Movistar in Spain and Maison de Bonneterie in the Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, specialized in mobile advertising, has measured user interaction rates up to three times superior on geolocation-based campaigns, compared to those that are not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its introduction to the advertising industry, geolocation has been quite a buzzword, perceived as one of the main advantages of mobile devices compared to PCs for advertisers. However, accurate geolocation has not been a useful tool for advertisers and brands in mobile display until recently. The biggest challenge has been that the reachable user base was very small, because accurate geolocation, unlike IP based geolocation, requires specific user&amp;#8217;s approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has started to change. Nowadays more users are willing to share their location with a simple click, as many mobile applications require it in order to meet their purpose. Within those apps users can naturally receive advertising campaigns that take into consideration their location. Thanks to the huge RTB (real time bidding) inventory and to companies such as mediasmart, it&amp;#8217;s now possible to launch geolocation-based campaigns with a big enough reach and great advertising effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart has developed campaigns that make extensive use of geolocation for clients such as Movistar in Spain and the shopping centers Maison de Bonneterie. In the Netherlands. As the company also optimizes the media buying process based on post-click events, advertisers are able to maximize results on their own physical stores by using coupons or similar devices. mediasmart has seen interaction rates up to three times higher in this type of campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noelia Amoedo, mediasmart&amp;#8216;s CEO, says: &amp;#8220;thanks to geolocation strategies, we can help clients connect with their public in the physical world, which is one step further in our mission to make mobile advertising as effective as possible.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why geolocation?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using geolocation on a mobile advertising campaign may or may not make sense depending on the goals of the campaign. These are some examples of how geolocation can be used effectively:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drive traffic to physical locations&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the advantages of geolocation is that advertisers with a physical presence can limit their campaign to the geographic area close to their points of sale, with the goal to drive traffic to their stores. Let&amp;#8217;s imagine an advertiser has a certain special offer in its stores. mediasmart can impact only users located within a few hundred meters of the stores, and, if the user clicks on the banner, it will open up a map with directions to the closest store and a discount coupon that can be redeemed in the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customize the message according to the location&lt;/strong&gt;: It is possible to adapt the advertising campaign to the user&amp;#8217;s location in order to maximize the conversion rate. For example, if a user is physically close to the advertiser&amp;#8217;s point of sale, (s)he will be shown an in-store offer and directions to the store. If the user isn&amp;#8217;t close to the store, (s)he will be shown a generic offer linking to the web, the mobile app or a call center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reaching your audience in a specific physical place&lt;/strong&gt;: It is possible to use geolocated campaigns to reach an audience whose interests are related to the service or product that is being promoted. Imagine, for example, how advertisers in the travel industry may want to run campaigns around airports or train stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart launches its new autoplay video format with Renault Capture, combining branding with real-time optimization</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-its-new-autoplay-video-format-with-renault-capture-combining-branding-with-real-time-optimization" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-11-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-11-12:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-launches-its-new-autoplay-video-format-with-renault-capture-combining-branding-with-real-time-optimization</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The online advertising company mediasmart allows advertisers to buying audience in real time (RTB). mediasmart has launched the new system format with the latest Renault Capture campaign for mobile devices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;media&lt;strong&gt;smart,&lt;/strong&gt; which specializes in the optimization of online mobile advertising campaigns, has just launched a new advertising format – &lt;em&gt;Interstitial Video Autoplay&lt;/em&gt; – which maximizes not only the notoriety, but also the visualization ratio in video campaigns. Through this video format, the mediasmart technological platform can precisely measure how much of a video a user sees (beginning, middle or full video) and optimize the media buying in real time based on those results (look-alike).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renault, together with mediasmart and its media agency – OMD – has been the first advertiser to test the new format with their Renault Capture campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the first time in Spain that an autoplay mobile video format is used to optimize the campaign in real-time, improving results with with each viewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video plays automatically in an &lt;em&gt;interstitial&lt;/em&gt; within mobile applications, and can be linked to a landing page with further information, if the advertiser chooses to do so. The format is currently available for iPhone and iPad, and will be shortly be also available also for Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Nuria Alonso, Commercial Director at mediasmart, “With the new &lt;em&gt;Interstitial Video Autoplay&lt;/em&gt; format, and through the mediasmart platform&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; we can provide our customers with a distinctive elementsome differential value, as they can measure and optimize a video format, which was traditionally not measured”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In OMD’s Tania Pérez Gacho’s words: “At OMD we have always looked for innovation for our customers, and with this campaign we have taken a step further in the combination of effectiveness and branding. For the first time in a video format, thanks to mediasmart’s technology, the campaign learns user behavior and optimizes in real time, targeting impacting more those users who are more likely to watch the video”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this new format, agencies and advertisers can reuse ad videos developed for other channels, such as television or computer, and effectively reach their target mobile audience, measuring the effectiveness by means of the display ratio. Considering that as of January 2013 Spain is 8 points above the European average with 57% of users going online from their mobile phones (doubled since December 2011), it is obvious that it is a channel that agencies and advertisers cannot neglectignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>On weekends, Spanish mobile users prefer to go online right after waking up</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/on-weekends-spanish-mobile-users-prefer-to-go-online-right-after-waking-up" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-11-06:mediasmart-pelican/blog/on-weekends-spanish-mobile-users-prefer-to-go-online-right-after-waking-up</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On weekdays and vacation, smartphone users use their mobiles more during the afternoon. The last report developed by mediasmart, through its mediasmart platform, analyzes, by day and time slot, the usage and mobile connectivity trends of Spanish smartphone users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart has revealed interesting information about the usage and connectivity trends of Spanish smartphone users; these results analyze the Internet usage in mobile devices during September, reference month that marks the beginning of the work year after the summer vacation. The data collected by mediasmart through its mediasmart platform show the comparison and Internet usage during the months of August and September, both in weekdays and weekends, and broken down by time slots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the weekends, users go online on their &lt;em&gt;smartphones&lt;/em&gt; right after waking up, while during weekdays and on vacation, users connect most on the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart has analyzed the behavior patterns in weekdays compared to weekends, as well as by time slot. While in August there was a similar connectivity pattern during the weekend and the weekdays, most Spanish users going back to work during September has given interesting results. In August and during weekdays in September, Spanish users connect to the Internet mostly after 3pm. During the weekends, however, the results of the mediasmart report show that users connect through their mobile device right after waking up, between 9am an noon, and show a balanced trend throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet usage from mobile devices increases during the weekend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During weekdays, mediasmart reports that there is a very similar usage from Monday to Friday, where there is a clear spike in traffic in the afternoon, after 3pm. However, there is a clear difference in user behavior during the weekend: both on Saturday and Sunday, users go online early in the morning, interacting with their mobile phone linearly during the rest of the day. The increase in traffic between 8am and 3pm leads to more advertising inventory generation during the weekend, compared to weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mediasmart wins the eAwards Prize 2013 as the Best Performance Marketing Agency</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-wins-the-eawards-prize-2013-as-the-best-performance-marketing-agency" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-09-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-09-26:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mediasmart-wins-the-eawards-prize-2013-as-the-best-performance-marketing-agency</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The company, specialized on the optimization of the media buying process for mobile display advertising, was competing with the other two finalists: Kanlli y Markitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart, a Spanish company specialized on the optimization of the media buying process for mobile display advertising, received the prize as the Best Performance Marketing Agency at the eAwards ceremony. This was the only prize that was not mobile specific awarded to a mobile company. The eAwards rewards every year the best business-to-business marketing strategies, aiming to develop actions, to guide and to optimize business relationships among companies. The prize also rewards the work of professionals in the industry for their excellence, innovation and professionalism at growing in global markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noelia Amoedo, mediasmart’s CEO, received the eAwards prize and highlighted the importance of such a prize for the company, as “it encourages us to keep offering our clients the best service, and helping them make their mobile display advertising campaigns as efficient as possible”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eAwards gathered popular votes through their website for a few weeks. mediasmart was chosen as one of the finalists for the Best Performance Marketing Agency – together with Kanlli and Markitude &amp;#8211; after adding up the popular votes and the votes of the jury. The jury &amp;#8211; made up of professionals in the space – then chose mediasmart as the Best Performance Marketing Agency of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, who works with direct clients as well as media agencies, has managed successful campaigns for important brands such as Vueling, McDonald’s, Nissan, Samsung or Mahou, using its own predictive targeting technology based on RTB:  mediasmart. mediasmart operates in Spain, but thanks to the scalability of its platform, it has launched campaigns in other countries such as Germany, France, Italy, Portugal and the U.S.A.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Mobile internet access increases in the summer</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-internet-access-increases-in-the-summer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-08-21:mediasmart-pelican/blog/mobile-internet-access-increases-in-the-summer</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The available inventory has increased by 23% in July with respect to the average of the 3 preceding months, according to data from the mediasmart platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all consumer habits of Spaniards change during summer and vacation.  One of the most noticeable is Internet access. While during the rest of the year the computer is the most used device to go online, in July and August the use of Internet access in mobile devices increases, as has been observed by the mediasmart´s ****team through their mediasmart platform, which optimizes the purchase of display media in smartphones and tablets and identifies user preferences with respect to advertisements in such devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the summer, the space available for brands to reach users through mobile Internet – either in mobile web or mobile apps – increases at least by 23%. Also, the traffic profile for mobile Internet changes geographically, with a marked increase in connections from coast and touristic areas (see map).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, and because it would be reasonable to assume that in leisure moments users are more willing to “explore”, it would be advisable for brands to allocate a larger percentage of their budget to mobile marketing during the summer, if they wish to maximize the reach of their advertising actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mediasmart platform targets audience and optimizes based on the combination of historical data from user profiles (interests, mobile operator, etc.) with context elements such as the publisher they are browsing, the time of day or the GPS position – this last one is a unique element of mobile marketing and a very powerful tool of present day advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Internet on the phone: From information to purchase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, 74% of smartphone users go online daily and 83% of those see the mobile ads that appear in their screens, according to a recent study by Ipsos, ‘Our mobile planet’, which also points out that 80% of users have looked for a product or service in their smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, in 41% of the cases the search from a mobile device develops into an online purchase. In this way, mobile advertising is creating a consumer trend in Spain, which is reflected in that 63% of the users who make purchases from their smartphones buy products from the phone at least once a month&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Spanish start up mediasmart raises additional capital to complete one million Euro in funding so far</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-spanish-start-up-mediasmart-raises-additional-capital-to-complete-one-million-euro-in-funding-so-far" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-07-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-07-11:mediasmart-pelican/blog/the-spanish-start-up-mediasmart-raises-additional-capital-to-complete-one-million-euro-in-funding-so-far</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the backing of well known investors in Europe, such as Kibo Ventures y KOMM, mediasmart doubles its initial investment of 500.000€. After one year in the market, the mobile advertising optimization platform has access to more tan two billion ad impressions per month in Spain, it processes about 5,000 bids per second and it has managed campaigns for such well known brands as Nissan, Vueling, Samsung or Mahou, to mention a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mediasmart, the Spanish company focused on optimizing the media buying process for mobile display, has completed a new round of financing with which it reaches one million Euro raised so far. With this new round, the company looks to consolidate its leadership position in the Spanish market, and to strengthen its technical platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this past year mediasmart has tripled its ****workforce, growing the development team, hiring campaign analysts and account managers, and creating a client services department. mediasmart offers both a personalized service and unique technology based on programmatic media buying (RTB), which makes buying decisions considering post-click events with a tangible value for advertisers: qualified visits, video views, calls, online registrations, visits to a physical store, etc…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, which works both with advertisers and media buying agencies, has successfully managed campaigns for such well known brands as Vueling, Nissan, Samsung or Mahou, using its proprietary technology platform, mediasmart. mediasmart is based in Spain, but thanks to mediasmart´s scalability, it has already launched campaigns in other countries, such as Germany, France, Italy, Portugal or USA. In addition to the advantage of optimizing media buying based on results, mediasmart can target campaigns to specific audiences, and segment based on mobile specific variables, such as the user´s location, the device and the type of connection the user is using to see the ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our platform learns from the user behavior and allows us to do predictive targeting. When buying media, it not only has into account contextual information, but also the historical information for that particular user and for the campaign, so that the price offered for each impression depends on the probability of that impression turning into the engagement we are looking for in the campaign - explains Noelia Amoedo, mediasmart´s CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During its first months mediasmart has grown a lot, multiplying its revenues by four. It offers access to more than two billion impressions per month in Spain, both within native applications and mobile web (in smartphones and tablets), having grown from half a million a year ago. mediasmart manages about 5,000 bids per second right now, and its scalable architecture is ready to easily increase this number with demand.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vueling entrusts the promotion of its mobile app to OMD and mediasmart</title><link href="http://jabesga.github.io/mediasmart-pelican/blog/vueling" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Ander Besga</name></author><id>tag:jabesga.github.io,2013-02-11:mediasmart-pelican/blog/vueling</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About 70% of the users who opened the application used it to search flight options, check in, reserve a seat or even buy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spain is a leading country in the app market, with 2.7 million downloads every day. However, as shown in a study developed by The App Date, the loyalty of users is very low: 13% would remove them and replace them with something similar. Free apps are one of the factors behind the compulsive downloading, and they are not always used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to increase the number of loyal users who download an app? The popular airline Vueling has found out, along with OMD and media&lt;strong&gt;smart,&lt;/strong&gt; with the promotional campaign of its new mobile app for iPhone and Android. The action is ongoing since November 2012 with the purpose of promoting the purchase of plane tickets through mobile devices while, at the same time, strengthening the dynamic and innovative image of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vueling’s goal was to go beyond traditional media to reach an audience who is interested in traveling. Thanks to OMD and mediasmart &amp;#8211; the technological platform of mediasmart &amp;#8211; Vueling has been able to ensure the campaign reaches those users who are willing to engage with their mobile app after having downloaded it. mediasmart technology maximizes the reach of campaigns thanks to its ability to build user profiles and measure their behavior after receiving an impression, which, together with real-time buying (RTB), allows it to find the optimal users no matter where they are browsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The campaign results have been very positive at both brand and conversion levels. The campaign has not only maximized the number of targeted users who have opened the application (not those who merely download it), but it has managed to get almost 70% of the users who open the application to use it to look for flights, check in, reserve a seat, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Vueling wants to make it easier to search, buy and manage flights, providing consumers with a useful tool. mediasmart´s technology, chosen by OMD, has allowed us to reach those users for whom we are really relevant, optimizing the campaign and improving how users perceive us”, added Nicola Riva, head of online marketing at Vueling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In OMD María Gil’s words: “At OMD we always go for innovation. The introduction of mobile technology and real-time bidding are altering the landscape of traditional media purchase, and taking us one step forward in establishing relationships with users. Companies with technology like mediasmart´s make it posible to go further in terms of effectiveness and branding”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noelia Amoedo, CEO of mediasmart concludes: “It’s an honor for us to have big agencies such as OMD and airlines like Vueling trust our technology. The results obtained are an endorsement of our constant strive for improvement”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>